Guide to the New York State College of Home Economics records, 1875-1979
Cornell University, New York State College of Home Economics records,
- Series XI: Photographs
  - Foreign Students and Visitors: African Woman
    - Rita Raymond talks with two African women about Extension (Box 77, Folder 33)
    - Frances Grauman talks about an Extension class with Victoria Mutswairo of Rhodesia (Box 77, Folder 33)
    - Frances Grauman, Dorothy Johnson and Victoria Mutswairo (of Southern Rhodesia) discuss topics of Extension Classes (Box 77, Folder 33)
    - Three African Women, visitors to the College, at a faculty picnic (Box 77, Folder 33)
    - Two African Women at a Barbecue (Box 77, Folder 33)
    - Two African Women dance and sing for College Professors, and other visitors, in the Big Red Barn (Box 77, Folder 33)
    - A picture of eight African Women on a bus (Box 77, Folder 33)
    - Group picture of the African Women Visitors (Box 77, Folder 33)
    - Two African Women examine an exhibit of Cornell Extension Homemaking Bulletins (Box 77, Folder 33)
    - An Assembly of the African Women in front of a bus (Box 77, Folder 33)
    - Miss Dorice A. C. Martinson, from Ghana (Box 77, Folder 33)
    - A warm handshake between Anne Row (Extension leader from Mexico, New York), and Margaret Kitchener Olowu (from Nigeria) (Box 77, Folder 33)
    - The African visitors are showing the children of the nursery school at the College of Home Economics at Cornell how to play a zebra-skin drum (Box 77, Folder 33)
    - Mrs. Olusola S. Banjo of Nigeria at barbecue (Box 77, Folder 33)
    - Verna A. Carley of the Agency for International Development and Mrs. Samira Seif of Zanzibar talking (Box 77, Folder 33)
    - Miss Dorice Martinson of Ghana makes a point in a discussion with food and nutrition Extension specialist, Professor Marjorie Burns (Box 77, Folder 33)
  - African Women Educators
    - A group of African Women and Marcia Robinson, student guide, at Ithaca Senior High School (Box 77, Folder 34)
    - Mrs. Efunjoke Coker, Nigeria, is introduced to American Barbecued chicken at faculty picnic (Box 77, Folder 34)
    - Mrs. Gulzar Sunderju of Kenya, boarding bus (Box 77, Folder 34)
    - African Women attending lecture by Professor Vera Caulum (Box 77, Folder 34)
    - group of African Women boarding a bus for Extension trips (Box 77, Folder 34)
    - Miss Mapoma and Miss Ogot are showing nursery school children at the College of Home Economics, Cornell, how to play a zebra skin drum (Box 77, Folder 34)
    - Efunjoke Coker and Marion Graves get acquainted (Box 77, Folder 34)
    - Carol Walien helps greet women educators at A La Mesa from Africa who visited the College of Home Economics, Cornell (Box 77, Folder 34)
    - An African visitor talks with a student at a tea in the College (Box 77, Folder 34)
    - Victoria Mutswairo (S. Rhodesia), and Sister St. Jeanne Laual U. (Quebec, Canada) (Box 77, Folder 34)
    - Mrs. Efunjoke Coker of Nigeria (Box 77, Folder 34)
    - African Women get a tour of the lockers by a student guide (Box 77, Folder 34)
    - Mrs. Lati Hyde-Forster (Sierra Leone) and Miss Lottie E.A. Hamilton-Hazeley (Sierra Leone) (Box 77, Folder 34)
    - Three African Women admire jewelry worn by Margaret Kitchener Olowu (Box 77, Folder 34)
    - Pamela Ogot (Kenya) and Ethel Mapoma (N. Rhodesia) (Box 77, Folder 34)
    - Ezerina Mwaipopo talks with students at an informal reception at the College (Box 77, Folder 34)
    - Students watch an African Woman show them how to tie a headpiece of her native costume (Box 77, Folder 34)
    - Reception with students at the College of Home Economics (Box 77, Folder 34)
    - Group Photo of the Visiting African Women (Box 77, Folder 34)
  - Visitors from other countries
    - Obdulia Sison, a graduate student in extension from the Philippines, Josephine King, a graduate student in institution management from Shanghai, China, and Gloria Mercado, a graduate student in institution management from the Philippines, talk with Margaret Hutchins, head of the department of Home Economics, at Farm and Home Week (Box 77, Folder 35)
    - The same three Asian women talk with Professor Helen Hoefer, of the department of home economics education at Farm and Home Week (Box 77, Folder 35)
    - Five woman educators from France visit the school; They sit and talk with Dean Elizabeth Lee Vincent, and Buelah Coon (Box 77, Folder 35)
    - Mrs. Ralph L. Sherer - librarian (Box 77, Folder 35)
    - Miss Bernarda Camello, Soedji Latifah, Dr. Jane Hanks, Dr. Presentacion Perez, and Dr. Hazel Hauck discuss international education in home economics and Southeast Asia (Box 77, Folder 35)
    - Two women talk about design (Box 77, Folder 35)
    - Two Indian women talk to two American women at the college (Two photos) (Box 77, Folder 35)
    - Dr. Elfriede Stubler, Freda William, Mrs. C.W. Willinge Prins-Visser, Karin Petersen, Dr. Kathleen Rhodes, and Helen Terre talk about international education in home economics and Northeast Europe (Box 77, Folder 35)
    - French educators and an American woman listening to headphones (Box 77, Folder 35)
    - A large map of the world with lines showing from which countries people have visited Cornell. Map titled: Home Economists to and from Cornell (Box 77, Folder 35)
    - Three new Chinese students at the college look over their books together at the steps of MVR (Box 77, Folder 35)
    - An Indian woman speaks at an international conference (Box 77, Folder 35)
    - Vu Stephen and Mrs. Joan Lulby of Australia - foreign students, 1952 (Box 77, Folder 35)
    - Mercedes Melchor (Philippines), Muna Khoury (Lebanon), Leonarda Jurado (Philippines), Iris Brunet (Puerto Rico), Zahida Quraishi (Pakistan): all graduates of the college, 1952 (Box 77, Folder 35)
    - Karen Mars and three others looking at a display, 1966 (Box 77, Folder 35)
    - A woman and a man look at a pamphlet together, 1966 (Box 77, Folder 35)
    - Margaret Brausfield Wood on the phone/at work, 1966 (Box 77, Folder 35)
    - Two people involved in a housing movie scene, 1967 (Box 77, Folder 35)
    - A happy reunion scene (Box 77, Folder 35)
    - Three new Chinese students at the steps of MVR, 1946 (Box 77, Folder 35)
    - A picture of a foreign student working (two photos) (Box 77, Folder 35)
    - An assembly of foreign visitors (Box 77, Folder 35)
    - Foreign graduate students: Muna Khoury, Leonarda Jurado, Iris Brunet, Zahida Quraishi, Mercedes Melchor (Box 77, Folder 35)
    - Margaret Harrington - FAO international member (Box 77, Folder 35)
    - A picture of a foreign student (woman) (Box 77, Folder 35)
    - A Persian design student, Monr Shahrudy, 1945 (Box 77, Folder 35)
    - Two students talk outside MVR (Box 77, Folder 35)
    - Mr. and Ms. Justo de la Paz with their two daughters leaving for Manila (Box 77, Folder 35)
    - Florence Theopholus and Professor Catherine Personius exchange greetings in the traditional Indian manner, 1959 (Box 77, Folder 35)
    - Professor Catherine Personius examines Florence Theopholus' sari, 1959 (Box 77, Folder 35)
  - Home Economics Exhibit
    - Getting ready for the JC Penney, McCall Fashion Show (Box 77, Folder 36)
    - Some women sample homemade cakes at the General Foods Exhibit (Box 77, Folder 36)
    - J. Folks at her desk (nutritionist) (Box 77, Folder 36)
    - Sara Blackwell explains life insurance to some young girls (Box 77, Folder 36)
    - Blackwell and a young man setting a table (Box 77, Folder 36)
    - An old Picture of the Homemaker Service in Cleveland Ohio; Two older women, a teenage girl and two young boys are baking (Box 77, Folder 36)
    - Miss Blackwell demonstrates cake baking to a group of students (Box 77, Folder 36)
    - A scene in the health center showing a dietetic intern, a doctor and a nurse (Box 77, Folder 36)
    - (ADA) A lunchroom scene at a middle school (Box 77, Folder 36)
    - Suffolk County - Department of Public Welfare. A woman is having a meeting with a staff member (Box 77, Folder 36)
    - YWCA-New York City; Two couples are dancing, four other people are present all drinking coca cola and looking at records (Box 77, Folder 36)
    - YWCA - New York City: Young wives group learning about color swatches (Box 77, Folder 36)
    - 4-H; M. Leighton and three young children learning to sew (Box 77, Folder 36)
    - 4-H Office; Two older children are leading a class for eight others (Box 77, Folder 36)
    - (ADA via Gottlieb) Two women demonstrating salad making to a group (Box 77, Folder 36)
  - Home Experiences
    - Former HDA and her convenient kitchen (Box 77, Folder 37)
    - A woman and a man painting a door, 1950 (Box 77, Folder 37)
    - A student teacher shows high school students how to arrange a winter bouquet, 1950 (Box 77, Folder 37)
    - Three girls doing some heavy duty cleaning in the kitchen (Box 77, Folder 37)
    - A young girl in the kitchen lab of home economics (Box 77, Folder 37)
    - A woman explaining the proper arrangement of a hat and glove drawer, 1956 (Box 77, Folder 37)
    - A woman creating her own sewing structure, 1946 (Box 77, Folder 37)
    - Two young girls learning how to organize the drawers in their bureau (Box 77, Folder 38)
    - A young girl learning how to organize the refrigerator (Box 77, Folder 38)
    - A young girl organizing the kitchen cupboards while being watched by her grandparents and younger brother (Box 77, Folder 38)
    - A view of an organized storage closet (Box 77, Folder 38)
    - Three women creating an organized kitchen cupboard (Box 77, Folder 38)
    - A relaxed scene of a woman reading a magazine in her living room (Box 77, Folder 38)
    - In the same room; a woman is putting away her linens (Box 77, Folder 38)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Photo from early 1900s of two women baking; Photo from early 1900s community canning class; Photo of women students working in shop class, molding metal, 1916, 1940-1949 (Box 101, Folder 19)
    - Consumers' Conference Luncheon, held at the Hotel Syracuse -Bond Bread (panorama), 1935-04 (Box 59, Folder 25)
    - A relaxing scene by the fireplace. Some women are knitting, some reading, some talking (Box 77, Folder 39)
    - A cafeteria scene at the register (Box 77, Folder 39)
    - Two women tying bags (Box 77, Folder 39)
    - A girl from the Ithaca Senior High School (Box 77, Folder 39)
    - A woman taking another woman's temperature. One appears to be a nurse (Box 77, Folder 39)
    - Some women fixing broken chairs (Box 77, Folder 39)
    - A woman restringing a bench (Box 77, Folder 39)
    - A woman being interviewed in an office by two other women (two pictures) (Box 77, Folder 39)
    - Two sisters posing for their school picture (Box 77, Folder 39)
    - An old picture of a woman ironing (Box 77, Folder 39)
    - A woman sitting at a man's feet (Box 77, Folder 39)
    - An example of how to make Christmas toys yourself (old photo) (Box 77, Folder 39)
    - Three women sewing and chatting (Box 77, Folder 39)
    - Chemung County Fair (Box 77, Folder 39)
    - Students learning to sew in a classroom (Box 77, Folder 39)
    - Girls studying in a room (Box 77, Folder 39)
    - Two people in an old style kitchen (Box 77, Folder 39)
    - A student enjoys reading "Teen-Age Mystery Classics", 1950 (Box 77, Folder 40)
    - Merna Samples (Center) listens to a talk on baking in someone's home. Four other people are also listening, while one woman is giving the talk (Box 77, Folder 40)
    - Two women are discussing the results they receive from their computer printout (Box 77, Folder 40)
    - A student teacher talks with a class about the seven main food groups one should include in one's diet everyday. A class of farm women listens to a lecture on fabrics and textiles (Box 77, Folder 40)
    - Four young women and a teacher go visiting an elderly woman in the community (three photos) A number of students learn how to use a washing machine, 1956 (Box 77, Folder 40)
    - Three students bake a cake together. They are learning to cream and fold the batter for Home Economics Education. A group of farm women knead and roll bread dough together (Box 77, Folder 40)
    - A student teacher demonstrating the ways a body moves using a wooden dummy. The title of the class is "Let your body work for you!" (Box 77, Folder 40)
    - A woman and a young girl serve a dinner that includes a member of each of the seven basic food groups (Box 77, Folder 40)
    - A student is admiring her reflection in a mirror. It is in the practice apartment three young children play with newborn mice at a laboratory. a group of women are having a serious discussion at a conference table, 1950 (Box 77, Folder 40)
    - An exhibit for the SUNY Home Economics educational opportunities. "Offers Home Economics Education for your daughter after high school" (Box 77, Folder 40)
    - A woman in the infirmary is visited by a nurse and two friends (Box 77, Folder 41)
    - Women creating a lining for a drawer (Box 77, Folder 41)
    - 4-H group in Ithaca: Two women demonstrate a drawer to four girls (Box 77, Folder 41)
    - Three women listen to records (Box 77, Folder 41)
    - Girl Scouts peeling potatoes, 1948 (Box 77, Folder 41)
    - A man and woman cooking in a small kitchen area (Box 77, Folder 41)
    - A man and woman sanding and cleaning wood furniture (Box 77, Folder 41)
    - A woman showing some onlookers how to peel an orange (Box 77, Folder 41)
    - A group of women sewing together (Box 77, Folder 41)
    - Two students bringing food to an elderly woman (Box 77, Folder 41)
    - A woman reupholstering a chair, 1946 (Box 77, Folder 41)
    - Three women testing out a shoe rack that they made (Box 77, Folder 41)
    - Mr. and Mrs. Arthur Davies (building maintenance supervisor)examine the floor plans of their home, 1961-07 (Box 77, Folder 41)
    - Mr. and Mrs. Arthur Davies (Box 77, Folder 41)
    - Mr. Davies' retirement party (Box 77, Folder 41)
    - College movie for Voice of America, Five women and a man sitting on a couch (Box 77, Folder 41)
    - Poultry Culling Demonstration (Box 101, Folder 4)
    - Home demonstration (Box 101, Folder 4)
    - Community Dinner, early 1900s (Box 101, Folder 4)
    - Engineering ,donated by Hannah Blumenthal Brown, 1931 (Box 101, Folder 5)
    - Demonstration Train (Box 101, Folder 6)
    - Housekeeping Leaders-Summer School, 1934 (Box 101, Folder 13)
    - Pantry with canned goods, 1947 (Box 101, Folder 14)
    - Play, 1920 (Box 101, Folder 15)
    - Student report with photos-Kitchen Efficiency in the Shoves Family (Box 101, Folder 16)
    - Children in kitchen (Box 101, Folder 17)
    - Home demonstration (Box 101, Folder 17)
    - Demonstrating household chores and good posture, 1915-1921 (Box 101, Folder 17)
    - Living Room-Decorated with greens, 1915 (Box 101, Folder 18)
  - Nursery School
    - A woman reads a book to children (Kenny La Bar, David Hill, Janita Ezell) (3 pictures) (Box 77, Folder 42)
    - Kathy Miller reads with Bobby LaDieu (Box 77, Folder 42)
    - Three boys listen to records with headphones (Box 77, Folder 42)
    - Boys learn how to saw wood and make shapes (Box 77, Folder 42)
    - Some nursery school children come in from the cold with their teacher (Box 77, Folder 42)
    - A teacher makes paper chains with children (Box 77, Folder 42)
    - Children try to carve on cement blocks (Box 77, Folder 42)
    - A girl and a boy clean the table (Box 77, Folder 42)
    - Children play on a gym set (four pictures) (Box 77, Folder 42)
    - Three children pose in the playroom (Box 77, Folder 42)
    - Four children eat outside with their teacher (Box 77, Folder 42)
    - Four children use a hammer and nails (Box 77, Folder 42)
    - A man shows some children a white rabbit (Box 77, Folder 42)
    - A girl touches the hamster in its cage (Box 77, Folder 42)
    - A little boy pretends to speak on a telephone (Box 77, Folder 42)
    - Children play in the sandbox (two pictures) (Box 77, Folder 42)
    - Children play outside (sunshine and snow) (four pictures) (Box 77, Folder 42)
    - A boy climbs a tree (Box 77, Folder 42)
    - Nine pictures of children playing inside. (they use blocks, dress up clothes, dollhouses and tea-sets), 1956 (Box 77, Folder 43)
    - Four pictures of snack time (Box 77, Folder 43)
    - The children play 'ring around the rosy" outside (Box 77, Folder 43)
    - Two at reading time (Box 77, Folder 43)
    - Two pictures of children at the entrance (Box 77, Folder 43)
    - Two children watering the plants (Box 77, Folder 43)
    - Three pictures of children baking (Box 77, Folder 43)
    - Children reading the "menu for Thursday" (Box 77, Folder 43)
    - Children playing in sandbox with Esther Stocks, 1940-1949 (Box 77, Folder 43)
    - Children in sandbox, Jean Powell, adult in sandbox, 1949 (Box 77, Folder 43)
    - Children playing in snow (Box 77, Folder 43)
    - Children playing on jungle gym outside (Box 77, Folder 43)
    - Students observing children in nursery school (Box 77, Folder 43)
    - Nursery School Children and College Student (Box 101, Folder 8)
  - Public Speech Contest
    - Elsie Van Buren Rice (Box 77, Folder 44)
    - Rice Stage contestants: Lorraine Kahn, Joanne Pakel, Carol Greene, Carol Muller, 1965-03-18 (Box 77, Folder 44)
    - Margaret Brown (chairwoman of the contest) discusses the criteria for judging the contest with Marlene Fries, and Mrs. William McMillan (daughter of James Rice) (Box 77, Folder 44)
    - Contestants: N.C.Paine, E. Rothermel, C.F. Wagner, E.H.Amsden, I.R. Adler, D.S.Smith: Group photo, 1954 (Box 77, Folder 44)
    - Barbara Benisch receives the prize. Also in the photo, Mrs. McMillan, Dean Betton, Joan Fulton, Gertrude Grover (Box 77, Folder 44)
    - Coffee hour, 1950-03 (Box 77, Folder 44)
    - Vivian Hoffman, Barbara Benisch, Doris Dittman, Joan Fulton, Martha Murrell, sitting in an auditorium (Box 77, Folder 44)
    - Three women posing (Box 77, Folder 44)
    - Joan Fulton, Dean Blanding, Barbara Benisch on stage (Box 77, Folder 44)
  - "Science at Work"
    - A woman uses a flammability tester for fabrics, 1963 (Box 77, Folder 45)
    - Professor Mary Morrison checks a tube of protozoa (Box 77, Folder 45)
    - Professor Henry N. Ricciuti Studies early signs of intelligence in infants, 1963 (Box 77, Folder 45)
    - Professor Karla Longree researching how to properly defrost a turkey, 1962 (Box 77, Folder 45)
    - Professor Mary S. Ryan and an assistant demonstrate a scale for women's likes and dislikes of clothing, 1963-07 (Box 77, Folder 45)
    - Dr. Esther Bratton shows that an easy relaxed posture is less fatiguing (Box 77, Folder 45)
    - Mrs. Harold Feldman, research assistant on reading (Box 77, Folder 45)
    - A woman tests insulating blankets, 1969-08 (Box 77, Folder 45)
    - Dr. Ruth Lutz uses men for study on Iron (Box 77, Folder 45)
    - Mrs. Jean Chen Lin testing an eggnog substance (Box 77, Folder 45)
  - State Fair Exhibits
    - "Fabric Finishes Engineered For Serviceability" pamphlet (Box 77, Folder 46)
    - A view of the exhibit. Different fabrics, and rainwear (Box 77, Folder 46)
    - Some of the posters: Spot and Stain Resistant Finishes How can Fabric Finishes Be Identified Different Finishes for Different Performances (Box 77, Folder 46)
    - Nina Adler examines a man's permanent press shirt at the exhibit (Box 77, Folder 46)
    - A man and a woman examine a new chair style (a photo and a group of pictures) (Box 77, Folder 46)
    - State Fair Exhibit "The Credit Supermarket", 1965 (Box 77, Folder 46)
  - Students
    - Two women leaving MVR - the Home economics building, after classes (Box 77, Folder 47)
    - Marilyn Jaff, and Nancy Fraser (Box 77, Folder 47)
    - Graduate students studying types of learning experiences (Box 77, Folder 47)
    - A group of students in a homemaking class plans ways of stretching the department budget so that they can entertain their friends, 1946 (Box 77, Folder 47)
    - Cornell students Doug MacLean and wife Sue do their "homework". They are with their son, Dougie. So that Dougie is never left alone, the MacLeans go to college on alternate days. Richard Suchman and Nancy Bird, students, 1952-1953 (Box 77, Folder 47)
    - Dean Elizabeth Lee Vincent presents diplomas to three graduates (Box 77, Folder 47)
    - Marilyn Gall, Barbara Fay Hochgrebe, Janet Steven (Box 77, Folder 47)
    - A young girl using a sewing machine (Box 77, Folder 48)
    - A young girl presenting a recipe to the class (Box 77, Folder 48)
    - Three young girls washing dishes (Box 77, Folder 48)
    - Four children learning how to saw wood (Box 77, Folder 48)
    - Two young girls experimenting with sewing (Box 77, Folder 48)
    - Three girls figuring out the problems of room arrangement (Box 77, Folder 48)
    - Three girls thinking about how to organize drawers (Box 77, Folder 48)
    - One girl modeling an apron that she made, 1950 (Box 77, Folder 48)
    - Three teenagers thinking about Christmas decorations (Box 77, Folder 49)
    - A girl looking for a can of food in a kitchen (Box 77, Folder 49)
    - A woman teaching some young girls how to use a sewing machine (two photos) (Box 77, Folder 49)
    - Three girls looking at skirts (Box 77, Folder 49)
    - Five girls getting a home economics education at Cornell (Box 77, Folder 49)
    - Kindergarten children are entertained at a valentine party given by 9th grade home economics pupils to crystallize learning in their study of child development, 1946 (Box 77, Folder 49)
    - Two young girls learning how to properly make a bed (Box 77, Folder 49)
    - Three girls setting up a living room (Box 77, Folder 49)
    - Two Photos of Winter Course in Home Economics-one includes Martha Van Rensselaer, 1917 (Box 100)
    - Home Economics Students in Ag-Engineering Class, 1940-1949 (Box 101, Folder 7A)
    - Students dressed as Native Americans (two photos) (Box 101, Folder 9)
    - Students cleaning house (Box 101, Folder 9)
    - Students setting table (Box 101, Folder 9)
    - Students in class, learning about dress (Box 101, Folder 9)
    - Students cooking (Box 101, Folder 9)
    - Male Home Economics students (Box 101, Folder 9)
    - Farm Research (according to label) - Woman lifting logs and students eating a meal (Box 101, Folder 21)
  - Identified People
    - A man holding up a cut of cloth for a group of interested women "Gibby Cornelius" is third from left (Box 77, Folder 50)
    - Four pictures of Gibby Cornelius and her students creating teaching tools and decorations (Box 77, Folder 50)
    - Father Zimmer is a guest speaker from the Rochester Diocese. He is talking with a group of varied and interested people (Box 77, Folder 50)
    - A kitchen scene: Jean Snyder (a teacher) is measuring a plate with a yardstick. A family is looking on (Box 77, Folder 50)
    - Jean Snyder, class of 1945, is chopping vegetables in a kitchen (Box 77, Folder 50)
    - Phyllis Stout, class of 1944, a student teacher at Ithaca High School (4th from L) (Box 77, Folder 50)
    - Miss Carbery and Betty Emmons help Mrs. Smith make a final check on the height of the working surfaces in the kitchen, before the plumber installs the new sink. Little Karen is fascinated by the procedure (Box 77, Folder 50)
    - Miss Carbery helps set up the cafeteria counter while Miss Fortune and Mrs. Osborne, the cook manager, discuss a necessary change in the menu for the next day (Box 77, Folder 50)
    - A slip-cover lesson for some women: Mrs. Hubert Walker, Mrs. Irene Rhodes, Mrs. N. Caletta, Mrs. Lewis Palley, Mrs. Fred Fernquist, Mrs. Charlotte Runey, Mrs. Wayne - Singer Sewing Machine Co. (Box 77, Folder 50)
    - A kitchen arrangement lesson: On the left is Ruth Franklin - Class of 1945 (Box 77, Folder 50)